Stijn Ortega Coppin

+44 7446 986316 <u>sortegac@gmail.com</u> https://uk.linkedin.com/in/stijnoc

Profile

As a results-driven product leader with over a decade in the tech industry, I excel at crafting customer-centric experiences and building and nurturing teams that are dedicated to delivering value. My expertise lies in balancing hands-on and strategic roles within international organisations, utilising data-informed decisions and empathetic approaches to product development across diverse cultures.

Highlights:

Product Development: Over 8 years of international product development experience in Asia, Europe, US, and Latin America.

Technology Leadership: 12+ years of technology experience, working with consumer-centric giants such as Apple, Michelin, and Toyota.

Team Building: A record of establishing diverse and collaborative teams, both remote and onsite, over the past 8 years.

Customer-Centric Approach: Proficient at developing empathetic, data-informed products that cater to user needs across various regions and cultures.

Experience

2020-Present: Michelin Connected Fleet - Group Product Manager | London, UK

At Michelin Connected Fleet, a fleet management and telematics company, I lead teams focused on vehicle management, geographical expansion, and replatforming.

- Initiated a segment strategy and roadmap from scratch (0-2 year horizon).
- Managed 3 full stack squads, hiring, training, and supervising 3 Product Owners and 2 Product Managers.
- Incorporated the Jobs To Be Done framework and OKRs into product cadence, instilling a culture of customer-centricity and incremental value delivery.
- Fostered a continuous discovery culture at all product levels.
- Introduced customer engagement and retention KPIs to track initiative impact and align teams with value delivery and positive growth loops.
- Owner of the infrastructure roadmap to converge Michelin's 3 telematic platforms into one, enabling easier geographic expansion, adaptability and faster value to market.
- Contributed to reducing churn by 50%, increasing ARPU on new opportunities by 20% in the segment, and facilitating sales and marketing to increase customer and unit numbers by at least 10% QoQ in the past 1.5 years.

+44 7446 986316 sortegac@gmail.com

https://uk.linkedin.com/in/stijnoc

2019: Toyota Connected - Senior Product Manager | London, UK

At Toyota Connected, a startup under Toyota's umbrella, I spearheaded Toyota's mobility strategy and product roadmap, managing a diverse cross-functional team of professionals.

- Created a cohesive global product roadmap for backend, mobile, and web products embodying
 7 distinct product streams covering mobility use cases and internal services.
- Launched and migrated 3 and 2 countries respectively, into our platform of mobility solutions in just 7 months.
- Implemented engineering, product, and management best practices, fostering a servant leadership mentality and a collaborative company culture.
- Led the MVP and soft launch of the first car manufacturer-led B2B2C corporate car-sharing solution in Europe.

2017-2018: Self Employed - Consultant | London, UK

As an independent consultant, I offered strategic guidance to SMEs, focusing on product development, business growth, and customer acquisition/retention.

- Developed a suite of solutions for a managed service provider, leading to an increase in revenue by £100,000/m through partnerships.
- Transformed a traditional bus for hire business into an experiential product, boosting profits by 20%.

2011-2016: Apple Inc. - Field Leader/Manager | London, UK

In a wide-ranging role at Apple, I oversaw all tech initiatives and partnerships within the EMEIA and APAC retail markets.

- Managed 150 stores across EMEIA with quarterly revenues in the 9-figure range, leading to the opening of 7 new countries and over 50 store launches.
- Developed, tested, and deployed 3 generations of Apple's own iOS-based POS and CRM solution (EasyPay)

2008-2011: Apple Inc. - Multiple Positions | Boston/Paris/London

Education

2004-2008: Colby College | Maine, US

Bachelor of Arts - Government - Davis Scholar

Additional coursework: Java, Inter-networking, GIS, Molecular Biology, Organisational Behaviour,

Economics, International Relations, Studio Photography

2002-2004: United World College of the American West I New Mexico, US International Baccalaureate recipient, National scholarship awardee

<u>Languages:</u> Fluent in English and Spanish, proficient in French, with a basic knowledge of NL, DE, PT, IT